Register of the Woodrow Wilson Issuances, 1914-1918
Hoover Institution Archives
Woodrow Wilson Issuances,
1914-1918
XX010
Wilson, Woodrow, 1856-1924
1 folder, 1 oversize volume 1 linear foot
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Executive orders and proclamations, relating to American neutrality, trade with belligerents, declaration of war, and establishment of defensive sea area during World War I
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
War and emergency legislation--United States.; World War, 1914-1918.; United States--Neutrality.; World War, 1914-1918--United States.; United States--Foreign relations.
Container List
- Executive Orders, 1917-1918 (Folder 1)
  - Executive order establishing defensive sea area, The White House, 1917 April 14 (No. 2597)
  - Executive order establishing defensive sea area, The White House, 1918 June 29 (No. 2898)
  - Executive order establishing defensive sea area, The White House, 1917 April 5 (No. 2584), regulations for carrying into effect the executive order of the President establishing defensive sea areas, The White House, 1917 April 5
  - Executive order respecting the exercise of the powers and authority and the performance of the duties of the Alien property custodian under the "Trading With the Enemy Act"..., The White House, 1918 February 28 (No. 2813)
- Proclamations, 1914-1918
  - Existence of war, German Empire, 1917 April 6 (No. 1364)
  - Exports in time of war, 1918 February 14 (No. 1428)
  - Imports in time of war, 1918 February 14 (No. 1429)
  - Neutrality, Panama Canal Zone, 1914 November 13 (No. 1287)
  - U.S. Neutrality in the Panama Canal Zone and with Belgium and Austria-Hungary, Japan and Germany, France and Austria-Hungary, Japan and Austria-Hungary, Washington, D.C., 1914 (5 documents)
- Address of President Wilson to the officers of the Atlantic Fleet, 1917 August 11
- Conspectus of special war activities of executive departments and independent establishments. Second edition. 1918 August 1. Washington, D.C. Government Printing Office, 1918 (1 oversize volume) (Other Map Case)